<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AD2 1DL231 :: AD2 Homepage</title><link>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/index.html</link><description>Webpage for assignments and lecture slides for AD2.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-uk</language><managingEditor>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</managingEditor><webMaster>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Syllabus</title><link>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/syllabus/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author><guid>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/syllabus/index.html</guid><description>Syllabus</description></item><item><title>Lectures</title><link>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/lectures/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author><guid>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/lectures/index.html</guid><description>Timetable and link to lectures</description></item><item><title>Assignments</title><link>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/assignments/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 11:49:26 +0200</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author><guid>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/assignments/index.html</guid><description>Overall Structure There are 3 mandatory assignments, to be done in alone, worth 2 higher-education credits (ECTS credits) in total.
The main objective of the assignments is to exercise the theoretical knowledge gained in the lectures. You are to hand in the code and a report. The code should follow the coding convention and the report must follow the structure and content of the demo report
For each assignment, the assistants supervise 3 help sessions for troubleshooting in the preparation of your reports.</description></item><item><title>Exam</title><link>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/exam/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author><guid>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/exam/index.html</guid><description>There is an individual, written, closed-book exam at the end of the course.
Some old exams can be found here.
Expected Effort One higher-education credit (ECTS credit) translates under Swedish university law into an expected 26.67 hours of work for the average student. Hence 133.33 hours are expected on this 5-credit course.
The exam is worth 3 credits. In addition to the exam preparation performed while working (during 90 hours) for the 2 credits for the assignments the remaining preparation and the taking of the exam are expected to take 24 hours. Recall that 19.5 hours are spent on the 13 lectures.</description></item><item><title>Recommended Exercises</title><link>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/exercises/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author><guid>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/exercises/index.html</guid><description>Recommended exercises from the CLR3 book for exam preparation. Don’t forget the book is available online at the University library. All these exercises are from the third edition. I don’t have the answers to the questions, and some of the exercises are non-trivial but will give you a deeper understanding of the material in book.
Chapter 15
15.1-2 15.1-3 15-2-2 15.4-1 15.4-2 15.4-3 Chapter 16
16.1-1 16.1-2 16.1-3 16.1-4 Chapter 21</description></item><item><title>Grades and Credits</title><link>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/grades/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author><guid>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/grades/index.html</guid><description>Assignments The three assignments are worth 2 higher-education credits (ECTS credits). The assignment grade is as follows when $a_i$ is your final score (out of 10) on Assignment $i \in 1..3$, and $a = a_1 + a_2 + a_3$ is your total score. Each assignment is divided into two Problems with sub parts. On each of the problems you must have a score of at least 1 (out of 5) to pass the course. If you have a 0 on any of the two problems any assignment, then you will fail the assignments.</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/resources/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 11:49:26 +0200</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author><guid>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/resources/index.html</guid><description>Text Book Thomas H. Cormen, Charles E. Leiserson, Ronald L. Rivest, and Clifford Stein. Introduction to Algorithms (fourth edition) The MIT Press, 2022. This will be referred to as CLRS4.
The second edition errata or third can also be used. The third edition will be referred to as CLRS3.
Note that it is now possible to access library resources online without being on the University network or using a VPN. You will be prompted for you CAS login. You need to go through the library search system. For the fourth edition follow this CLRS4 and for the third edition follow this CLRS3.</description></item><item><title>Contact, Help, Ethics and FAQ"</title><link>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/contact/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author><guid>https://ad2-uu-se.github.io/contact/index.html</guid><description>Before contacting anyone for help, please check whether your question has an answer in the FAQ list below. If not:
If you have a question about the lecture material or course organisation, then contact the head teacher.
If you have a question about the assignments or infrastructure, then contact the assistants at a help or solution session for an immediate answer. Short clarification questions (that is: not about programming issues) that are emailed to the AD2 helpdesk are answered as soon as possible during working days and hours. No answer means that you should go to a help session: almost all the assistants’ budgeted time is allocated to grading and to the help, grading, and solution sessions.</description></item></channel></rss>